Nishan Khadka

25 Highland Terrace, Little Mountain, QLD 🏫

0450379372



Nissankhadka5@gmail.com



Along with my studies, on one hand, I tried starting up my own Tech company with my friends but failed to do enough business and eventually, we were forced to shut it down in the month of June 2018. We failed because of our professionalism. Hence, I moved to Australia in June 2019 and started my master's degree in information technology. Here I learned lots of Professional behavior, company culture and the role of teamwork in the project management. I was doing my full-time study so you can see the 2 years of gap in my work experience i.e., from 2019 to 2021. Now, I am a junior software developer at Urban Software Institute, Sippy Downs, Sunshine Coast. I am always keen to learn new things and currently I am more in UX UI design

Experience

JAN 2022 - PRESENT

Junior Software Engineer/Urban Institute, Sippy Downs, Qld

- Develop and deliver fit for purpose software that meets end- user requirements
- Support with the documentation of the organization's business processes
- Actively undertake and participate in software quality assurance
- Use DevOps to manage tasks daily to ensure all assigned tasks are completed and delivered according to organizational priorities Handle external data securely and confidentially
- Identify new improvements in procedures and technologies that can add value and improve efficiencies in the delivery of systems and interfaces
- Test and deploy programs and systems
- Willingness to assist and support others as required to meet deadlines
- Responsible for estimating, planning and managing all our own tasks and reporting on progress
- Mentor and supervise interns when required
- Participate in the development of a healthy and safe workplace, embracing initiatives, information and training.
- Demonstrate safe work behaviors, abiding by procedures, identifying and reporting hazards, and contributing to all aspects of a safe workplace culture
- Such other relevant duties as required from time to time which would generally fall within the scope of this position.

APRIL 2015 - JUNE 2018

Founder/ Frontend Developer/Lightweb Group Pty Ltd, Kathmandu, Nepal

- Met with the client and did all the software engineering requirements following the agile methodology
- Interview with the stakeholders to point out the changes they wish to see in the new system
- Provided PHP, CSS, Bootstrap, WordPress training to the juniors
- Took IT department contract of different Business.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.

 Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.

APRIL 2015 - SEPT 2018

Graphic Designer/Gaurav Printing Press and Stationary Suppliers, Chitwan, Nepal

- Generated digital image files for use in digital and traditional printing.
- Worked with customers to present mockups and collect information for adjustments.
- Developed engaging marketing and promotional advertisements to generate sale revenue and grow customer base.
- Directed advertisement, banner and signage projects from concept to final delivery.
- Developed website layouts, templates and unique branded looks for educational projects.
- Developed, designed, laid out and produced variety of technical illustrations for brochures, banners and signs.

Skills

Web Development • HTML5 • CSS/CSS3 • Bootstrap • CMS • SEO • DevOps • Git• Ubuntu • SQL • Adobe InDesign• Adobe PhotoShop• Adobe Illustrator•

Education

JULY 2019 - SEPT 2021

Masters in Information Technology (System Analysis)/Charles Sturt University, Brisbane, Australia

AUG 2015 - SEPT 2018

Bachelors in Information Technology/University of Northampton, Northampton

AUG 2013 - SEPT 2015

High School in Pure Science/Aroma College(Physics)

Activities

• Snooker • Trekking • Bike Riding • Gym • Travelling • Trying new dishes • Learning